In this clip, we'll actually be ear candling.
So, you've got your tray and you've got your candle, and you need some flames.
You light the end of your candle.
And you see that the candle actually is hollow.
What this creates, it creates a full seal, like a draw from the flame through the hollow tube of the candle.
And it creates a suctioning effect from the end of the candle, which you will insert into your ear, gently but firmly creating a seal.
Now, if smoke starts to appear down here, I know I don't have a good seal.
And, so, if you're alone, hopefully, you have a friend, but if you're alone, have your mirror handy so you can watch and see what's going on.
You want the candle to be as vertical as possible.
And you'll notice the tray is here, the tin foil tray, to protect my head.
And if any ashes end up falling they'll land right into the tray.
The candles themselves don't have much wax.
They're gauze, like I mentioned, sort of dipped in wax and then made in this hollow shape, so there's no wax from the candle dripping down on you.
The suction that the fire creates through the candle is drawing the wax out of your ear.
It's good to do this once, maybe twice a year.
And at the season change is the best time, especially from winter to spring.
Now once the candle has burned down to the point of a couple of inches from your tray, and you can use your handy mirror; looks like I'm there.
This is where your bowl of water comes in handy.
You simply remove the candle from your ear, being careful, and remove it from the tray, and then drop the end in the water.
And if you're a curious fellow, you could cut the end of the candle and take a look at what came out of your ear.